What's going on guys?
Hope you're doing amazing.
In this video I want to show you how to implement a bidirectional LSTM in PyTorch.
So what we're going to do is I have some code set up here which is just some very simple
code, some training loop, check accuracy, and the loading damage dataset.
This is from my previous video if you want to check this out.
And what we want to do is we want to create a bidirectional LSTM.
And what we're going to do is we're going to do class.
Let's call it bidirectional BRNN.
And we're going to inherit an en module.
And we're going to do define init.
And yeah, let me just mention here that.
So what we have is we have the MNN dataset.
And MNN is dataset we can view as having 28 sequences which each has 28 features.
So the image is a 28 by 28 grid.
So we can kind of unroll it row by row.
And we can feed that to the RNN sequentially so that each, we have 28 timestamps and each
timestamp just takes a single row of the image.
And then we just have some number of layers that we're going to use.
We have the hidden size of the RNN.
Just some parameters and the number of classes learned later, etc.
But we're going to send in to the bidirectional RNN.
It's just to emphasize the hidden size, the number of layers and the number of classes.
We're going to do super B RNN self and then dot init.
And then we're going to do self that hidden size is just hidden size.
Self that numb layers is just numb layers.
And then we're going to define our LSTM and we're going to nN dot LSTM, input size and then hidden
size, number of layers that's just sort of the order where we send it in.
And then we're going to batch first equals true for the MNN dataset which has batches as
the first axis.
And then just to make it bidirectional, all we have to do is bidirectional equals true.
So easy, no, I guess.
And then we're going to do self that fully connected is an endot linear and we're going to
do hidden size to a number of classes.
And then so we know forward.
Just one thing that we need to keep in mind is that we'll we need to define our hidden state
and also the cell state that we're going to send into LSTM.
And yeah, so let's do that.
H0 will be our hidden state towards that zeros and we're going to do self that numb
layers.
And then we're going to times that by two.
And why we do that is that so we have self the number of layers.
But we also have, let's see, so we have, so we have self the numb layers.
And then we need to times it by two since we have one of them going forward.
And one of them going backward.
But they're all going to get concatenated into the same specific hidden state.
So we need to just expand this tensor by two in this axis.
And then we're going to do x dot size of zero just a number of examples we send in.
And so the back size and then self that hidden size.
And then just dot to the device.
Okay, and actually we need to do that here as well.
So the end of the linear will take the hidden size by times two since for the same argument.
We have one going forward, one going backward.
And they're going to get concatenated.
And that's sort of the hidden state from that particular time sequence.
Yeah, just some background from bi-directional LSTM.
I'm sort of assuming in this video that you know the theory behind it.
And this is just the sort of the implementation of it.
And yeah, so we can just copy this for the cell state.
And then we just need to sort of run the LSTM and the H0, cell state in a two pool.
And what would be the output here is the is the is the hidden state.
And then the cell state.
But we're not really going to use those.
So we can just remove or we we don't have to look at that output.
And then we're just going to do out is.
cell.fc of out and we're just going to take the last hidden state sending to the linear layer.
And then we're just going to return out.
And yeah, all we need to do here is we need to.
Inish lies in network with the B RNN and this should be ready to run.
So I'm going to run this for guess two e-packs and let's see what kind of results we get.
So training for two e-packs we get nine about 97% accuracy, which is I guess not too great.
But yeah, we're just training for two e-packs.
So you could I guess expand this as well.
And you would probably get a lot better accuracy.
But yeah, that was that's pretty much it for the bi-directional alicim.
If you have any questions, leave them in the comment.
Otherwise, thank you so much for watching the video and I hope to see you in the next one.